Narrator: Girl by O. Henry
Detective: I’ve found where she lives.
Here’s the address.
She moved there a week ago.
I can follow her if you want.
It will only cost you $7 a day and expenses…
Hartley: No, thank you.
I only wanted the address.
How much is it?
Detective: One day’s work, ten dollars.
Narrator: Then Hartley left his office and took a tram to Broadway.
After walking a short distance he arrived at the building that he was looking for.
He went up the stairs into her apartment,
and saw her standing by the window.
Hartley: Vivienne, you didn’t answer my last letter.
It took me a week to find your new address! Why didn’t you answer me?
You knew I was waiting to see you and hear from you.
Vivienne: Mr Hartley, I don’t know what to say to you.
I understand all the advantages of your offer,
and sometimes I feel sure that I could be happy with you.
But, then sometimes I am less sure.
I was born a city girl, and I am not sure that I would enjoy living a quiet life in the suburbs.
Hartley: My dear girl, you will have everything that you want.
You can come to the city for the theatre, for shopping,
and to visit your friends as often as you want.
You can trust me,
can’t you?
Vivienne: I can trust you completely, I know you are the kindest of men,
and that the girl who you get will be very lucky.
I heard all about you when I was at the Montgomerys’.
Hartley: Ha ha! I remember so well the evening I first saw you at the Montgomerys’.
I will never forget that dinner.
Come on, Vivienne, promise me.
I want you.
Nobody else will ever give you such a happy home.
Tell me, Vivienne, is there…is there someone else?
Vivienne: You shouldn’t ask that, Mr Hartley, but I will tell you.
There is one other person…but I haven’t promised him anything.
Hartley: Vivienne, you must be mine.
Vivienne: Do you think for one moment,
that I could come to your home while Héloise is there?